Finding Aid for the Memorial to WillHard Brownell Jewell
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Memorial to WillHard Brownell Jewell
multiple
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0229
16.32 linear_feet
Biographical Sketch
Jewell, Wlllard B(rownell), born in Little Compton, R.X., April 4, 1899. Graduated from Mount Harmon 3ohool for Boys 1918, Seaman U.S. Navy Sept. 1918 - Deo. 1918, Ships Carpenter U.S. Merchant J'arine Feb; 1919 - Aug. 1919, PhB Brown Univ. 1923, PhD Princeton Univ. 1926, Asst. Prof. Vanderbllt Univ. 1926-1938, Abso. Prof. Vanderbilt 1938-., Visiting Prof, of Geology, Summer Sohool, Colorado College 1935, Direotor Vanderbilt Summer Pield Trip in Geology, sunmers of 1929, 1930 and 1936. Asst. U.S. Geol. Survey (Alaskan Branch) 1924-1925, Aeao. Geologist (part time) Tenn. Geol. Survey 1927-. Asst. Geologist, Newfoundland Geol. Survey 1937. I am a member of the Tenn. Acad, of Science and the Soc. of Scon. Geologists. Publications and research on the Coast Range Intr&sivea of Alaska and British Columbia, Mineral Deposits of the Salmon River Area, Hyder District, Alaska, Geology and liinere.1 Resources of Hardin County, Tenn., Geology and Mineral Deposits of the Bale d'Espoir Region, Newfoundland and Barite-Fluorite-Sphalerlte-Galersa Veins of Central Tennessee.
Course Geology 281
Text Textbook of Geology, Part I, Physical Geology by Longwell, Knopf and Plint.
Course Outline The course consists of three hours of lectures and one three-hour laboratory period each week for the first half of the sohool year. The laboratory work includes a half term on rooks and minerals, seven or eight exercises on topographic contour maps and one or two exercises on geologlo structures. The lectures cover Rooks and Minerals, Atmosphere, Rain and Running Water, Underground Water, Lakes and Interior Drainage, The Ocean, Organic Life as a Geological Agent, Glaoiation, Vuloaniom, Dlastrophism, Deformation of Rooks, Physical State and Constitution of the ISarth’a Interior, fountains, Physiographic Divisions of the United States, Ore Deposits.
Exhibits A large number of exhibits are used in the course suoh as typical specimens of rooks and minerals, physiographic models, a working geyser model, structure blocks, meteorites, specimens showing the effects of glaoiation, vulcanism, crystal! lzati solution, sedimentation, etc but these cannot be removed from the building.
Examinations Sample examinations are attatched. I request that no Vanderbilt student be allowed to see these examinations and that they be returned to me when they have served your purpose.
W. B. Jewell.
Obituary:
It is with sorrow, regret, and a deep sense of loss that the Faculty of the College of Arts and Science records the passing on June 21, 1969, of WILLARD BROWNELL JEWELL, professor emeritus of geology, after forty two years of most distinguished service to Vanderbltt University.
The Faculty extends Its deepest sympathy to the family of Professor Jewell and hopes that they will find some small measure of comfort in the assurance that the University and his colleagues will long revere his memory and be grateful for his outstanding stature as a scholar, teacher, and administrator as well as for the many other Indispensable and varied services he rendered the University.
Wlllard Brownell Jewell was born on April 4, 1899, In Little Compton, Rhode Island, where he was returned to rest. He attended the public schools there until he entered Ht. Hermon School In the Connecticut Valley of Massachusetts in 1915. He graduated from Mt. Hermon In 1918 and the following autumn enrolled In Brown University. His freshman year was Interrupted, but after part of a year as a petty officer In the Merchant Marine he returned to Brown and graduated with honors In 1923. He then went to Princeton University for his graduate work and received his Ph.D. In Geology there In 1926.
While at Princeton, Dr. Jewell married Ann Hennessey of Fall River, Massachusetts. Their children are John William, Barbara Ann Pond, and Richard Brownell.
In September. 1926, Or. Jewell came to Vanderbllt University as Assistant Professor of Geology. He remained at Vanderbllt rising to Associate Professor in 1937 and to full Professor and Chairman of the Department of Geology In 1942. He early Interested himself In university affairs - curriculum, counseling, teaching, and students. He served on many university committees, often as chairman, such as those on the Advisory System, Athletics, Senior College, Veterans, Curriculum, Student Christian Association, Library, Natural Sciences, and Faculty Committee to the Board of Trust. He was elected an original member of both the Faculty Council and the University Senate. He served as Chairman of the Campus Committee tn the $30 Million for Vanderbllt Campaign, and for fifteen years was secretary of the College of Arts and Science Faculty.
Dr. Uewell's professional work ranged from Alaska and Newfoundland to Tennessee and North Carolina. His primary Interest was always the study of mineral deposits, both ores and Industrial minerals. The results of these studies have been published principally in bulletins of various geological surveys.
He was a member or fellow of several professional societies including The Geological Society of America, and served as chairman of tits Southeastern Section, in 1962 he was president of the Tennessee Academy of Science. He was a member of ODK, Sigma Xi, and Phi Beta Kappa. He served as president of the Vanderbllt chapters of Sigma XI and Phi Beta Kappa. From 1949 to 1951 he was a member of the Tennessee Conservation Commission under Governor Brown Ing.
Professor Jewell was also a great teacher. No matter how busy, he was always glad to drop whatever he was doing and talk to students about their problems, scholastic or otherwise. His advice was sympathetic and objective and consequently, highly respected. (This was similarly true of his relations to younger colleagues.) His lectures and explanations always started with first principles or historical background and on these firm foundations, he built, logically and objectively, the thesis or conclusion that seemed best to fit the facts. This objectivity characterized also his relations with his colleagues and his attitude toward his work. His salty New England speech and humor were trademarks.
Those of us who had the very great fortune to serve as his associates, or were closely connected with him In other capacities, will treasure as long as we live his unfailing friendliness and good humor; his courage and intellectual honesty; his example of sound scholarship and duty to truth and principle. Professor W. B. Jewell was one of vanderbllt's Great Hen.
_____________________________(date)
_____________________________
Richard G. Stearns
_____________________________
Herbert Weaver
_____________________________
Charles W. W1lson, Jr.
It Is here moved that a copy of this Memorial be Included in the Minutes of this meeting of the Faculty of the College of Arts and Science, and that copies be sent to each member of his family.
- W.B. Jewell Files
  (Note: The following may be taken as a general indication of the contents of these files, which have not been sorted and are in the order in which they were sent to the Archives.)
  - Minutes (Appendices), College of A & S Faculty (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Duplicate faculty minutes, Sept. 23, 1941 - June 8, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Faculty resolutions (death & retirement) (Box 1)
  - Faculty minutes (duplicates), June 20, 1945 - June 4, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Faculty minutes (duplicates), July 6, 1948 - June 6, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Faculty minutes (duplicates), Sept. 19, 1952 - June 4, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Faculty minutes (duplicates), Sept. 24, 1954 - June 1956 (Box 1)
  - CM.A. evaluation (Box 1)
  - Student Christian Association (Box 1)
  - Faculty Club (Box 1)
  - Dr. Tom Zerfoss (Box 1)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Key Reporter (Box 1)
  - Semester System (Box 1)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 1)
  - Sigma Xi (Box 1)
  - Vanderbilt University Press (Box 1)
  - University Senate (Box 1)
  - Science Fair (Box 1)
  - Shop Committee (Box 1)
  - Branscomb Professorship (Box 1)
  - Thruston Collection (Box 1)
  - Division of Natural Sciences (Box 2)
  - JUL Committee (Box 2)
  - Vanderbilt Comm. - Names (Box 2)
  - Omicron Delta Kappa (Box 2)
  - Vanderbilt Comm. - General (Box 2)
  - Athletic Committee (Box 2)
  - YMCA (Box 2)
  - WSSF (Box 2)
  - Smoke Abatement (Box 2)
  - Princeton-Vanderbilt Program (Box 2)
  - Mr. James L. Buford - Senior College Material (Box 2)
  - Memoranda for Advisers (Box 2)
  - Student Publications Board (Box 2)
  - Branscomb Dinner, Dec. 20, 1962 (Box 2)
  - $30 Million for Vanderbilt Campus Drive (Box 2)
  - Dean Shahan (Box 3)
  - Dean Smith (Box 3)
  - Vice-Chancellor Stambaugh (Box 3)
  - Faculty Advisory Program Committee (Box 3)
  - Cromwell, William Cook (Box 3)
  - Senior College Committee Minutes, 1935-37 (Box 3)
  - Dean Crawford (Box 3)
  - Joint Faculty-Student Committee on Student Union Lectures (Box 3)
  - Faculty Handbook (writeup of Faculty Meetings) (Box 3)
  - Dean Davidson (Box 3)
  - Dean Pomfret (Box 3)
  - Cars and Trucks (Box 3)
  - Veterans Council (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Study of American Men of Science (Box 3)
  - Advisers 1936-37 (Box 3)
  - Instruction and Guidance Committee (Box 3)
  - Jr. and Sr. College Committees 1936-37 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - Geography - Pre-Met. (Box 4)
  - Correspondence - Geography - A.S.T.P. (Box 4)
  - Pre-Meteorological Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Geography - Pre-Meteorology (Box 4)
  - Tennessee Academy of Science - Editor, Geology Sect. - 1961- Exec. Comm., Feb. '63 (6 folders) (Box 4)
  - Tennessee Junior Academy of Science, Oak Ridge, June 1963 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence files, A-K (Box 4)
  - Correspondence files, L-Z (Box 5)
  - Tennessee Survey Work - corresp. (Box 5)
  - Tennessee Geological Survey - corresp. (Box 5)
  - Chancellor - corresp. (Box 5)
  - GSA (Southeastern Sect.), 1954- - corresp. (Box 5)
- Outgoing correspondence, 1927-1960, is arranged chronologically. Date and in parentheses, name of addressee are given for each letter.
  - 10 Nov. (Frank Jewell), 1927 (Box 1)
  - 15 April (Horace M. Albright} L.B. Lambert), 16 May (Theo. Bergmann), 20 Hay (W.M. Winton), 1 Oct. (J.H. Kirkland), 28 Oct. (R.D. Lyne), 12 Dec. (Mrs. Charles Abbott), 1930 (Box 1)
  - 22 Jan. (Charlie Evans; Hichard Field; Ben Howell), 6 Feb. (The Hobard Bros.) 13 Feb. (The Kellogg Air Compressor Co.), 16 Feb. (T.G .Andrews), 1? March (W.T. Thorn), 17 March (T.G. Andrews), 5 Hay (W.T. Thorn'; W.A. Kelly), 19 May (Joseph K. Roberts), 9 June (P.D. Houston), 11 June (C.E. Brown; Ed Sampson; Joseph K. Boborts), 29 Sept. (Prof. E.H. Kraus), 5 Oct. ( George M. Flint), 22 Oct. (George M. Flint, Jr.), 5 Nov. (George M. Flint, Jr.), 12 Dec. (Mr. Mason), 1931 (Box 1)
  - 3 June ( The Coleman Lamp and Stove Co.), 12 Oct. (John Wiley and Sons), 5 Dec. (Kendall E. Born), 27 Dec. (The Toy Tinkers; Denoyer-Geppert Co.; L.D. Goodspeed, Inc.), 1932 (Box 1)
  - 11 Jan. (Prof. W.T. Thorn, Jr.), 12 May (Prof. W.T. Thorn"}, 3 June (Prof. W.T. Thom), 4 Oct. (Prof. R.P. Meachan), 10 Oct. (Mrs. R.D. Lyne), 1933 (Box 1)
  - 10 Jan. (Dean F.C. Paschal), 19 March (Dr. T.G. Andrews), 4 April (Mr. George Brown), 16 Sept. (Prof. J.E. Carman), 1934 (Box 1)
  - 8 May (Dr. Arthur Smith), 3 Oct. (Muncie Gear Co.), 0 Oct. (Mr. W.W. Spurgeon), 1935 (Box 1)
  - 6 March (Allstate Insurance Co.), 15 April (Dr. A.K. Snelgrove), 29 April (»r. A.K. Snelgrove), 11 May (Mr. J.T. Fisher), 1936 (Box 1)
  - 10 May (Southern Saddlery Co.), 15 May (Southern Saddlery Co.), 24 Sept. (Bergmann Shoes),Berlin Glove Co.; Dr. Edward Sampson), 27 Sept. (Dean F.C. Paschal), 27 Oct. (Berlin Glove Co.; Bergman Shoe Co.) 5 Oct. (Mr. J.T. Rooney), 11 Oct. (A.P. de Sanno and Son, Inc.), 1 Nov. (Dept. of Conservation -- St. of La.), 16 Nov. (Bausch and Lomb Optical Co.), 11 Dec. (Norton Co.), 1937 (Box 1)
  - 10 Feb. (Prof. Paris B. Stockdale), 28 May (Muncie Gerar Co.), 10 Nov. (Mr. John D. Rommel), 1938 (Box 1)
  - 8 Feb. (Dean Fred J. Lewis), 28 Feb. (Thurston Supply Co.), 18 April (Mr. J.R. Steelman), 26 April (Mr. John J. Stonborough), 27 April (Prof. Alonzo Quinn), 31 May (Dr. A.K. Snelgrove), 5 June (Dr. A.K. Snelgrove; Professor Brown), 10 June (Mrs. Martha McBride Morrel) 24 Sept. (Mr. Overton Williams), 12 Oct. (Wm. Dixon, Inc.), l2 Oct. (Prof. C.H. Behre, Jr.; Mr. E.J. Kennedy, Jr.), 12 Dec. (Mrs. Martha McBride Morrel), 1939 (Box 1)
  - 15 April (Bauech and Loan Optical Co.), 22 April (Prof. C.H. Behre), 1 May (David S. Spain), 20 May (Air Conditioning Headquarters, 1940 (Box 1)
  - 6 Jan. (Bell and Howell Co.), 15 March (Bill), 26 May (Bausch and Lomb Optical Co., 29 May (W.W. Grainger, Inc.), lj June (Prof. A.F. Bud-dington), 3 July ( Mr. Glendon Moore), 19 Sept. (Prof. Alonzo Quinn), 1 Oct. (Denoyer-Geppert), 2 Oct. Central Scientific Co.), 6 Oct. (Condolidated Bus Co.), 8 Oct. (Denoyer-Geppert Co.; Dr. D.F. Fleming) 17 Oct. (Mr. Lee Douglas), 28 Oct. (Eversharp, Inc.), 18 Nov. (Ever-shapp Inc.), 19 Nov. (Geology Dept.), 21 Nov. (Mineral Supply House) 3 Dec. (Eversharp, Inc.; Mineral Supply House), £ Dec. (Mr. Clarke Prather), 1941 (Box 1)
  - 9 Jan. (Mr. James A. White), 17 Jan. (Mr. O.E. Davis; Miss Frances Scruggs) 21 Jan. (McGraw-Hill Book Co., Inc.), 28 Feb. (Dean Fred J. Lewis), 12 Feb. (The Geographical Press; Prof. Charles Nevin; Prof. Alonzo Quinn), 16 Feb. (Mr. Sukyoon Chang), 2 March (Bausch and Lomb Optical Co.), 9 March (Dean F.C. Paschal), 1 April (K.G. Rucker Co.), 10 April (Dr. W.P. Fisher), 13 April (Cullum and Ghertner; Mr. Overton Williams), 15 April (Mr. Louis Bircher; Prof. Donald Davidson; Prof, flohn Hyden), 5 May (Mr. Joe Booker; Prof. Knox Chandler), 8 June (Mr. Overton Williams), 9 June (Mr. E. Glendon Moore; Mr. Clarence Walker), 18 July (Mr. E.E. Bryan), 21 July (Mr. Frank Alexander; Joe (E.G.) Moore; Mr. Clark B. Tippens), 25 July (Local Board No. 5), 4 August (Dr. E.F. Burchard), 5 August (Dr. C.H. Behre, Jr.), 6 August (Mr. George F. Crowl), 8 Aug. (Local Board No. 5; Dr. Frederic H. Lahee), 10 August (Mr. Wes Brown; Ward's), 19 August (Mr. George H. Crowl), 20 August (Dr. E.F. Burchard; Dr. Paul MacClintock), 29 Aug. (Thurston Supply Co.), 3 Sept. (Thurston Supply Co.), 3 Sept. (Sears Roebuck and Co.), 4 Sept. (Mr. O.E. Davis - HcQudiddy Printing Co.; Thurston Supply Co.) • 25 Sept. (The Administrative Committee), 30 Sept. (The Mineral Supply House; Mr. Glendon Moore), 13 Oct. (Cullom and Ghertner Co.; Mr. Joseph B. Eastman; Mr. O.E. Davis - McQuiddjtyPrinting Co.; Molecular Models), 15 Oct. (Mr. R.A. Redfield), 22 Oct. (Denoyer-Geppert Co.; Molecular Models), 28 Oct. (Estwing Mfg. Co.), 2 Nov. (Molecular Models), 13 Nov. (Mr. John C. McCampbell; Mr. A.H. Mitchell); l8 Nov. (The Curriculum Committee), 28 Nov. (The Jersey Farms Milk Service; W.C. Russell Moccasin Co.), 10 Dec. (Mr. C.Edward Graves; Mr. John C. McCampbell; Mr. Glendon Moore; The W.C. Russell Moccasin Co.; Mr. R.N. Williamson; John Wiley and Sons, Inc.) 31 Dec. (The Geographical Press), 1942 (Box 1)
  - 6 Jan. (Mr. W.H. Courtier), 7 Jan. (Denoyer-Geppert Co.; Mr. M. Makar - John Wiley and Sons, Inc.), 9 Jan. (Sears Roebuck and Co.), 19 Jan. (The Birmingham Ordnance District; Eastman Kodak Co.), 20 Jan. (Denoyer-Geppert Co.; Rand McNally & Co), 21 Jan. (E.P. Dutton & Co., Inc.; harcourt Brace & Co.; Harcourt Brace & Co.; Harper & Brothers; Keystone View Co; Mr. Byron C. Marshall - Ozark Biol. Labs.; Odyssey Press; Prentice-Hall, Inc.; Rand McNally and Co.; Mr. S.J. Reginald Saunders ), 22 Jan. (Bausch & Lomb Optical Co.), 25 Jan. (Spencer Lens Co.), 27 Jan. (Mr. J.R. Cudworth-- School of Mines; Denoyer-Geppert Co.; Harcourt-Brace & Co., Inc.; Ward's Natural Science Estab., Inc); 29 Jan. (Eastman Kodak Stores; Willoughby's Cawra Stores), 5 Feb. (Central Scientific Co; Denoyer-Geppert; 5 Feb. (Mr. Dudley Meek - Harcourt, Brace & Co.; Keystone View cont. Co.; Dean C.M. Sarratt), 9 Feb. (Eastman Kodak Stores, Inc.; Ensign W.D. Hardeman; Mr. G.M.D.E. Varennes; Willoughby Camera Stores, Inc.) 13 Feb. (Pvt. Frank M. Alexander; Bean's, Inc.; Major Will T. °heek; Mr. L.R. Curie - Amer. Georg. Soc; Mr. J.B. Dixon; Mr. E.J. Foreman; Mr. M.G. Gustin), 20 Feb. (Dr. F.C. Paschal), 22 Feb. (Mr. R.O. Johnson), 25 Feb. (L.L. Bean, Inc.; Rand McNally & Co.), 24 March (Mr. Curtis G. Benjamin), 25 March (Pvt. E.G. Moore), 19 April (P.F.C. Lindon T. Cookley), 22 April (Mr. E.S. Gardner), 28 Aprii (Mr. E.J. Foreman), 6 May (Mr. H.H. Ward; Mr. Lee Hager; Hr. E.J. Foreman); 11 May (Erpi Classroom Films, Inc.), 2 June The Geographical Press), 5 June (Erpi Classroom Films, Inc.), 122June (The Geographical Press), 15 dune (McGraw-Hill Book Co.), l8 June (Hr. George H. Crowl; Kewaunee Manuf. Co.; Pvt. E.G. Moore; Mr. D.P. Murphy; Ward's Natl. Science Estab., Inc.; Western Mineral Exchange), 25 June (Mr. G.H. Crowl; Mr. D.P. Murphy), 2 July (Dr. Paris B. Stockdale), 5 July (Mr. D.P. Murphy), 9 July (Hr. George H. Crowl; Prof. Paris B. Stockdale), 11 July (Mr. D.P. Murphy), 19 July (Mr. J.C. Babcock), 23 July (The Geographical Press), 28 July (Mr. Wlm. A. Bievins), 6 August (Mr. L.E. Pitner), 23 August (Dr. C.S. Chadwickj Lt. George F. Roe; Mr. Hill Turner), 27 August (Mr. Frank Ware), 30 August (Henry Holt and Co.), 6 Sept. (Miss Harriett Joanne Farrell; Seal, Inc.; Mr. Frank Ware), 22 Sept. (E.p. Dutton & Co.), 23 sept. (Miss Elinor Fieming; Miss Margaret Enid Knox), 1 Oct. (Prof. George Crowl; Kewaunee Manuf. Co.; Mr. M.M. Christensen; Dr. Paris B. Stockdale), 15 Oct. (Mr. H.C. Gimiand; Mr. L.E. Pitner; Mr. N.A. Rose), 25 Oct. (Mr. Herman W. Ferguson), 27 Oct. (Erpi Classroom Films, Inc.; Dean F.C. Paschal), 25 Oct. (Prof. Paris B. Stockdale) 1 Nov. (The Chemical Rubber Co.), 10 Nov. (Ens. W.O. Hardeman), 3 Dec. (Denoyer-Geppert Co.), 13 Dec. (Pvt. Frank M. Alexander; Mr. Byron C. Marshall; Cpl. E. Gien(j[on Moore; Ward's Natl. Science Bulletin), 20 Dec. (Mr. Byron C. Marshall), 23 Dec. (Denoyer-Geppert Co.; Sgt. Joseph Sifford); 28 Dec. (Mr. Byron C. Marshall), 30 Dec. (Denoyer-Geppert Co; Mr. Dudley Meek), 1943 (Box 1)
  - 11 Jan. (Mr. Harry P. Graves), 18 Jan. (Pfc. Frank M. Alexander), 18 Feb. (Prof. George Crowl), 21 Feb. (Mr. S.R. Bumann; Erpi ulassroom Films, Inc.), 23 Feb. (Denoyer-Geppert Co.; Mr. E.S. Gardner; Mr. E.S. Gardner; Mr. E.S. Gardner), 25 Feb. (Mr. H.R. Aldfich; Mr. Fitzgerald Hall; Mr. F.H. Lahee) 3 March (Film3 of Commerce Co., Inc.), 20 March (Mr. C.H. Templeton), 22 March (Denoyer-Geppert Co.; General Biological Supply House, Inc.; General Science Service); 31 March (Mr. Chester A. Newby), 3 April (Mr. George urowl; Mr. A.H. Mitchell; Mr. C.R. Templeton), 10 April (Mr. O.E. Geppert -- Denoyee-Geppert Co.; Pvt. A. Royfe), 22 April (Mr. O.E. Geppert - Denoyer-Geppert Co.; CharleB S. Sawyer Co.), 5 May (Central Scientific Co.), 8 May (Denoyer-Geppert Co.), 5 June (Pvt. Frank M. AieKander), 27 June (Mr. George Crowl), 23 August (Mr. Harry P. Graves; Miss Mary Caroline Lumpkins), 25 Aug. (Eastman Kodak Co.; Mr. Byron C. Marshall; Ward's Natl. Science Estab.) 28 Sept. (Mr. P.K. Denk - Eastman Kodak), 12 Oct. (Mr. Edward Graves; xenn. lialley Authority), 14 Oct. (L.L. Bean, Inc.), 30 Oct. (Mr. O.E. Datis, McQuiddy Printing Co.), 4 Nov. (Parker Pen Co.), 1944 (Box 1)
  - 1 Jan. (E. Edelmann & Co.), 11 Jan. (Dr. A.F. Buddington; Mr. Janes L. Buford; Hr. Robt. A. Laurence; Hr. Root. H. Ross; Ward's Natl. Science Estab., Inc.), l8 Jan. (Pvt. C.E. Jones), 19 Jan (Eastman Kodak Co.), 25 Feb. (T/5 E. Glendon Moore), 7 March (Dean Kenneth Condit; Pres. John Pomfret), 8 March (Pfc. Frank M. Aiexan<ier. Pfc. C.E. Jones; T/k E. Glendon Hoore; Mrs. E. Glendon Moore), 15 March (Mr. Walter J. Murphy; Prof. L.I. Smith), 27 March (Prof. Harris B. Stockdale), 12 April (Dr. Wayland J. Hayes), 5 May (Dr. Wayland Hayes; Prof. L.I. Smith; Ward's Natl. Science Estab., Inc.), 22 May (Parker Pen Co.; Mr. Ollie Smith, Jr.; Ward's Natl. Science Estab., Inc.), 1 June (Green Industries; Mr. Frank Habere; Mr. R.C. Vance), 20 June (Jas. L. Buford), 25 June (Green Industries; Mr. Ollie Smith, Jr. ), 6 July (Green Industries), 7 July (Mr. & Mrs. John Jewell), 17 July (Mr. H.W. Ferguson A/S), 24 July (Time, Inc. ), 22 Sept. (Time, Inc. ), 27 Sept. (Estwing Manuf. Co.; Mr. Herman W. Ferguson; Green Industries; Mr. N.A. Rose), 9 Oct. (Time, Inc. ), 22 Oct. (Mr. George Crowl; Lt. (jg.) Lynn Farrar, Jr.; Time, Inc.), 7 Nov. (Prof. Paris B. Stockdale), 20 Nov. (Mr. H.W. Ferguson; Dr. John McCampbe 12 Dec. (Lt. (jg.) R.L. Farrar, Jr.; H.W. Ferguson; The W.C. Russell Mocessin Co.), 1945 (Box 1)
  - 14 Jan. (Dr. George Crowl; The Hamilton Watch Co.; Newspaper Printing Corp.; Dr. E.G. Rasmussen; Ward's Natl. Science Estab.), 15 Feb. (Mr. H.W. Ferguson; Mr. C. Edward Graves; Green Industries; Mr. Dale Lambert; Dr. Arthur C. McFarlan; Prof. M.A. Sjteinmayer; Dr. Paris B. Stockdale; Mr. John H. Webb; Dr. Lawrence Whitcomb), 5 March (Mr. Milton Avery), 6 March (Thurston Supply Co.), 8 March (Dr. T.G. Andrews; Lt. R. Lynn Farrar, Jr.; Mr. E. Edward Graves), 18 Harch (The Andrew Technical Service), 19 March (Newspaper Printing Corp.), 29 April (Dr. T.G. Andrews; Mr. Dale Lambert; Dr. E.G. Rasmussen; Ward's Natl. Science Estab.,, Inc.; John Wiley and Sons, Inc.), 20 May (Natl. Roster of Scientific and Specialized Personnel), 10 June (Mr. & Mrs. W.B. Brown; Mr. Overton Williams), 15 June (Time, Inc. ), 26 Sept. (Time, Inc. ), 17 Oct. (Mr. George M. Flint), 9 Nov. (Hotel Stephens), 12 Nov. (American Technological Co.; Mr. Charles Blankenship; The Central Scientific Co.; The Lustro Co.); 12 Nov. (Dr. Joe W. Peoples; Ward's Natl. Science Estab.), 26 Nov. (Mr. Walter F. Pond), 10 Dec. (Mr. R.C. Vance), l8 Dec. (Dr. Joe Webb Peoples), 1946 (Box 1)
  - 7 Jan. (Miss Patricia Mahen), 9 Jan. (Dean Waller S. Leathers), 21 Jan. (Mr. E. Edward Graves), 11 Feb. (Denoyer-Geppert Co.; The Hamilton Watch Co.; Mr. Floyd Johnson; Seal, Inc.), 25 Feb. (Mrs. Edward H. Anderson; Dr. Arthur C. McFarlan), 4 March (Mr. Donald K. Mackay; Mr. John E. Meyer), l8 Mar. (Denoyer-Geppert Co.) 8 April (Prof. Kendall E. Born; Seller Instrum. Co.), 15 April (D.T. Davis Co.; Albert A. Henning & Co.,; Mr. R.C. Vance) 22 April (Mr. Eric Seller - Seller Instrument Co.) 28 April (Dr. G.H. Crowl), 29 April (Mr. J. Hayman; Prof. Kendall E. Dorn. Mr. J.E. Swisher, Jr.; Mr. R.C. Vance), 1 Hay (Denoyer-Geppert Co.), 3 Hay (Claude K. Howse), 6 Hay (Hr. John E. Swisher, Jr.), 13 May (Mr. S.A. Wahl), 27 May (Mr. R.C. Vance), 10 June (Mr. W. Bradford Wiley), 16 June (Time), 1 Oct. (Bausch & Lomb Optical Co.; Mrss Madeline Pond) 23 Oct. (Mr. George Carpenter, Jr.; Dean Meredith Crawford; Mrs. Walter F. Pond), 28 Oct. (Mr. Shepard W. Lowman; Mr. Walter F. Pond), 4 Nov. (Tenn. Valley Authority), 11 Nov. (Dr. Lawrence Whitcomb), 18 Nov. (Mr. H.O. Anderson), 2 Dec. (Andrew Technical Service; Mr. S.A. Weakley), 9 Dec. (Mr. D.K. Mackay; The Readers Digest), 16 Dec. (Hr. W.B. Brown), 1947 (Box 1)